{"data":{"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","address":"2700 Martin L King Jr. Blvd","zipcode":"48208","owner":"metz culinary management","licenseNumber":"221011","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","mostRecentLicenseDate":"8/3/2018","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":null,"reviewFrequencyDays":"180.0","geom":"0101000020E61000007003E0CD8AC554C020777185312B4540","inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"42903","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","inspectionDate":"2018-07-16T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"87","pcount":"0","pfcount":"0","ccount":"0","criticalcount":"0","noncritical":"0","correctedcritical":"0","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"43370","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","inspectionDate":"2018-07-10T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"87","pcount":"0","pfcount":"0","ccount":"3","criticalcount":"0","noncritical":"3","correctedcritical":"0","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"43370","inspectionDate":"7/10/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"6-303.11","violationDescription":"Light of the proper intensity shall be provided as specified.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Lighting intensity","subItem":"at 30 inches above the floor","problemDescription":"Not maintained","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Under the Ventilation hood","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Maintain in good repair"},{"inspectionid":"43370","inspectionDate":"7/10/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"6-201.11","violationDescription":"Except otherwise approved, and except for antislip floor coverings or applications may be used for safety reasons, floors, floor coverings, walls, wall coverings, and ceilings shall be designed, constructed, and installed so they are SMOOTH and EASILY CLEANABLE.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"wall(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not constructed, designed, installed to be","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Over WALK-IN COOLER","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Repair/replace to be smooth and easily cleanable."},{"inspectionid":"43370","inspectionDate":"7/10/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN FREEZER","subLocation":"Under the Condenser","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"41195","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","inspectionDate":"2018-01-09T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"87","pcount":"0","pfcount":"0","ccount":"7","criticalcount":"0","noncritical":"7","correctedcritical":"0","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"41195","inspectionDate":"1/9/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"floors","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"STORAGE ROOM","subLocation":"On the Floor","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"inspectionid":"41195","inspectionDate":"1/9/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"FRONT COUNTER/AREA","subLocation":"Under the Sink","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"inspectionid":"41195","inspectionDate":"1/9/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"6-303.11","violationDescription":"Light of the proper intensity shall be provided as specified.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Lighting intensity","subItem":"at work levels","problemDescription":"Not maintained","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Under the Ventilation hood","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2018-01-09T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Maintain in good repair"},{"inspectionid":"41195","inspectionDate":"1/9/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"4-602.12","violationDescription":"(A) The FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of cooking and baking EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at least every 24 hours. This section does not apply to hot oil cooking and filtering EQUIPMENT if it is cleaned as specified in Subparagraph 4-602.11(D)(6).   \r\n(B) The cavities and door seals of microwave ovens shall be cleaned at least every 24 hours by using the manufacturer's recommended cleaning procedure.","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Microwave oven door seals and cavities","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"Through out the day as necessary","location":"DINING AREA","subLocation":"Inside the Microwave Oven(s)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean as specified above."},{"inspectionid":"41195","inspectionDate":"1/9/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Broken","subProblem":"","location":"DINING AREA","subLocation":"At the ACCESS","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Repair/replace."},{"inspectionid":"41195","inspectionDate":"1/9/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"4-204.112","violationDescription":"(A)  In a mechanically refrigerated or hot FOOD storage unit, the sensor of a TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICE shall be located to measure the air temperature in the warmest part of a mechanically refrigerated unit and in the coolest part of a hot FOOD storage unit.\r\n(B)  Cold or hot holding EQUIPMENT used for POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD shall be designed to include and shall be equipped with at least one integral or permanently affixed TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICE that is located to allow easy viewing of the device's temperature display (EXCEPT, heat lamps, cold plates, steam tables, or other equipment where it is not practical).\r\n(C)  TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES shall be designed to be easily readable.\r\n(D)  FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES and water TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES on WAREWASHING machines shall have a numerical scale, printed record, or digital readout in increments no greater than 1C or 2F in the intended range of use. (Pf)\r\n\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Thermometer(s)","subItem":"refrigeration","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"FRONT COUNTER/AREA","subLocation":"At the Cooler (upright)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide as required"},{"inspectionid":"41195","inspectionDate":"1/9/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"floors","problemDescription":"With accumulation of debris","subProblem":"","location":"DISHWASHING AREA","subLocation":"On the Floor","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."}]},{"inspectionid":"39334","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","inspectionDate":"2017-07-25T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"124","pcount":"1","pfcount":"1","ccount":"2","criticalcount":"2","noncritical":"2","correctedcritical":"2","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"39334","inspectionDate":"7/25/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"6-301.12","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with:\r\n(A) Individual, disposable towels; (Pf)\r\n(B) A continuous towel system that supplies the user with a clean towel;(Pf) or \r\n(C) A heated-air hand drying device.(Pf)\r\n(D) A hand drying device that employs an air-knife system that delivers high velocity pressurized air at ambient temperatures.(Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Sanitary hand drying provisions","subItem":"disposable, paper towels","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"At hand sink","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"At the Handsink","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-08-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide"},{"inspectionid":"39334","inspectionDate":"7/25/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"FRONT COUNTER/AREA","subLocation":"At the Cold holding equipment","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-07-25T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store below 41 degrees F."},{"inspectionid":"39334","inspectionDate":"7/25/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"4-202.18","violationDescription":"Filters or other grease extracting EQUIPMENT shall be designed to be readily removable for cleaning and replacement if not designed to be cleaned in place.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Ventilation hood filter(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"At the Grease extraction filters","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2017-08-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"inspectionid":"39334","inspectionDate":"7/25/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"4-903.11","violationDescription":"Cleaned EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, laundered LINENS, and SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES shall be stored in an approved manner and location.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Single-service/single-use article(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored on floor or less than 6 inches above floor","subProblem":"","location":"REAR STORAGE ROOM","subLocation":"On the floor Single service items","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2017-08-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store at least 6 inches above the floor."}]},{"inspectionid":"37892","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","inspectionDate":"2017-01-24T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"124","pcount":"5","pfcount":"3","ccount":"2","criticalcount":"8","noncritical":"2","correctedcritical":"8","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"37892","inspectionDate":"1/24/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"3-305.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be protected from contamination by storing the FOOD:\r\n(1)     In a clean, dry location;\r\n(2)     Where it is not exposed to splash, dust, or other contamination; and\r\n(3)     At least 15 cm (6 inches) above the floor, unless otherwise approved.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Food item(s) in storage","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored on floor or less than 6 inches above floor","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2017-02-22T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store at least 6 inches above the floor."},{"inspectionid":"37892","inspectionDate":"1/24/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"7-201.11","violationDescription":"POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL shall be stored so they can not contaminate FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES by:   \r\n(A) Separating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL by spacing or partitioning; (P) and   \r\n(B) Locating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL in an area that is not above FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.  This paragraph does not apply to EQUIPMENT and UTENSIL cleaners and sanitizers that are stored in WAREWASHING areas for availability and convenience if the materials are stored to prevent contamination of FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES. (P)","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Poisonous/toxic material(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored over/with","subProblem":"Single-service/use items","location":"CAFETERIA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-01-24T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store toxics below and away from all other items."},{"inspectionid":"37892","inspectionDate":"1/24/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"3-101.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be safe, unADULTERATED and honestly presented. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Food","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Dishonestly presented","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-01-24T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"inspectionid":"37892","inspectionDate":"1/24/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-01-24T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store below 41 degrees F."},{"inspectionid":"37892","inspectionDate":"1/24/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Sanitizer test kit","subItem":"quaternary ammonia","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-01-24T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide."},{"inspectionid":"37892","inspectionDate":"1/24/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"2-101.11","violationDescription":"A PERSON IN CHARGE shall be present in the FOOD ESTABLISHMENT during all hours of operation. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not present","subProblem":"","location":"PERSON IN CHARGE","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-02-22T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"A Person in Charge is required to be present during all hours of operation."},{"inspectionid":"37892","inspectionDate":"1/24/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"2-301.14","violationDescription":"FOOD EMPLOYEES shall clean their hands and exposed portions of their arms as specified under § 2-301.12 immediately before engaging in FOOD preparation including working with exposed FOOD, clean EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, and unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES (P) and:\r\n(A)     After touching bare human body parts other than clean hands and clean, exposed portions of arms; (P)\r\n(B)     After using the toilet room; (P)\r\n(C)     After caring for or handling SERVICE ANIMALS or aquatic animals as specified in ¶ 2-403.11(B); (P).\r\n(D)     Except as specified in ¶ 2-401.11(B), after coughing, sneezing, using a handkerchief or disposable tissue, using tobacco, eating, or drinking; (P)\r\n(E)     After handling soiled EQUIPMENT or UTENSILS; (P)\r\n(F)     During FOOD preparation, as often as necessary to remove soil and contamination and to prevent cross contamination when changing tasks; (P)\r\n(G)     When switching between working with raw FOOD and working with READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\r\n(H)     Before donning gloves for working with FOOD; (P) and\r\n(I)      After engaging in other activities that contaminate the hands. (P)","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Employee(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Did not wash hands","subProblem":"","location":"EMPLOYEE(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-01-24T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Hands shall be washed with hot water and soap for at least 20 seconds after contamination."},{"inspectionid":"37892","inspectionDate":"1/24/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"floors","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"DRY STORAGE AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2017-02-22T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"inspectionid":"37892","inspectionDate":"1/24/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"2-301.14","violationDescription":"FOOD EMPLOYEES shall clean their hands and exposed portions of their arms as specified under § 2-301.12 immediately before engaging in FOOD preparation including working with exposed FOOD, clean EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, and unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES (P) and:\r\n(A)     After touching bare human body parts other than clean hands and clean, exposed portions of arms; (P)\r\n(B)     After using the toilet room; (P)\r\n(C)     After caring for or handling SERVICE ANIMALS or aquatic animals as specified in ¶ 2-403.11(B); (P).\r\n(D)     Except as specified in ¶ 2-401.11(B), after coughing, sneezing, using a handkerchief or disposable tissue, using tobacco, eating, or drinking; (P)\r\n(E)     After handling soiled EQUIPMENT or UTENSILS; (P)\r\n(F)     During FOOD preparation, as often as necessary to remove soil and contamination and to prevent cross contamination when changing tasks; (P)\r\n(G)     When switching between working with raw FOOD and working with READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\r\n(H)     Before donning gloves for working with FOOD; (P) and\r\n(I)      After engaging in other activities that contaminate the hands. (P)","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Employee(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Did not wash hands","subProblem":"during food prep to prevent cross contamination","location":"EMPLOYEE(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-01-24T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Hands shall be washed with hot water and soap for at least 20 seconds after contamination."},{"inspectionid":"37892","inspectionDate":"1/24/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"1640","name":"University of Detroit Dental School","violationCode":"6-301.12","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with:\r\n(A) Individual, disposable towels; (Pf)\r\n(B) A continuous towel system that supplies the user with a clean towel;(Pf) or \r\n(C) A heated-air hand drying device.(Pf)\r\n(D) A hand drying device that employs an air-knife system that delivers high velocity pressurized air at ambient temperatures.(Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Sanitary hand drying provisions","subItem":"disposable, paper towels","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"At hand sink","location":"CAFETERIA","subLocation":"At the Handsink","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-02-22T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide"}]}]}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"1640"}}